Rahul Tomar

Software Developer

+91 8319968379

Rahultomar092@gmail.com

https://github.com/rahuloo5

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rahul-tomar-941586116/

Summary

I am a self-taught developer specializing in JavaScript, React and React Native. I have learned through building and deploying apps, pushing to GitHub and getting peer code reviews on LinkedIn and twitter. Because of my contagious enthusiasm and passion for learning I got apperception from many developers on twitter. I love the daily challenges of web and App development: writing quality code, learning new technologies, and solving complex problems. I have been continuing to learn through opportunities comes. I look forward to working on a team that is passionate about their product.

I want to make things that make a difference.

TECH STACK JavaScript | React js | React Native | Node | Express | MongoDB | Bootstrap | Git

Work History

React-Native: 2020-present

- Building a cross-platform mobile app using React-Native and the Expo-cli.
- Responsible for designing and building the front end of the application.
- Implementing user login, access to camera, and social media sharing options.
- Communicating with the client to determine requirements and meet expectations.

Web-Developer: 2020 -present

- Built many dynamic websites for e-commerce, pharmacy and management
- Integrate front end with backend and made queries using graphQl
- Integrated payment option with website.
- Set up embedded live stream and live chat capabilities.

Project Engineer: 2018-present

Handle user -issues related login/authorization.

Handle exception of front-end and backend of Reports/Interactive-View Which

users face and resolve them in production.

Manage Unix and Cloud Servers Hypervisor, Red Hat, Patching activities and

their Utilization

Support Quarterly release of production websites and its related Apps.

Work on scripts that automate the daily issues that users face.

Projects:

Websites:

Burger Builder: Using basic concepts of Reactjs ,jsx and JavaScript made burger Builder .Here user can

add indigents and remove and make burger of its choice

Link: https://burgerbuilder-65dde.web.app/

The Last Wish: In this Website We Provide Funeral Services to families of every religion with different

packages and complete last wish of a person

Link: https://thelastwiish.web.app/

Medicine: Using basic concepts of E-commerce, I made website where I sell products related to

Pharmacy

Note: please signup and submit you automatically login

Link: https://dabbai.web.app/

Weather Reporting: In this website It simply shows temperature of any city/country.

Link: https://mausamcast.web.app/

APPS

Food Recipe: Using dummy data created Food Recipe App using React Native, JavaScript, redux

Link: https://expo.io/@rahul 55/khanakhazana

Activity Tracking: In this i created Time Tracking App where user can start and stop time and add activity which he wants to perform.

Link: https://expo.io/@rahul 55/timer

Instagram Image Scroll View: in this App, I created Image scroll functionality like Instagram where user can like and comment on any Picture.

Link: https://expo.io/@rahul_55/scrollimage

Airbnb: In this App, I simply created UI of Airbnb

Link: https://expo.io/@rahul 55/airbnb

Food Swipe: in this App we use tinder swipe animation to add favorite food in cart or reject food

Link: https://expo.io/@rahul_55/FOOD

Coca-Cola: Simple UI of Coca-Cola clone

Link: https://expo.io/@rahul-55/cococola

EDUCATION

Educational Qualification	Year	Institution/Board	% Marks/CGPA
B.E.(EC)	2017	Jabalpur Engineering College, Jabalpur	72
CBSE XII	2012	Kendriya Vidyalaya no.4, Gwalior(M.P.)	81.2
CBSE X	2010	Army Public School, Gwalior(M.P.)	81.7

Extra Curriculars Activities:

- College level Kabaddi player.
- House Captain in school, represent house in every competition
- Member of Core Team Coordinator in college to organize college fest and functions.
- Participated in cricket and football competition at school and college level.
- Participated in 100days code challenge

Interests

- Coding
- Movies
- Cricket
- Philanthropy